Guide to the Joan Preiss Papers, 1970-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Joan Preiss papers 1970-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Preiss, Joan Papert
54.0 linear feet Extent: 40,500 Items
Community and labor movement organizer in Durham, N.C.; chair of the Triangle Friends of the United Farm Workers; board member of the National Farm Worker Ministry; member of the Farmworker Ministry Commission, N.C. Council of Churches. Accession (2009-0279) (40,500 items; 54.0 lin. ft.; dated 1970-2006) includes Preiss's personal papers as well as organizational records from her role in the Triangle Friends of the United Farm Workers (TFUFW), the National Farmworker Ministry (NFWM), the Farmworker Ministry Commission, and the AFL-CIO's Farm Labor Organizing Committee (FLOC). Each of these organizations worked to improve the lives of farmworkers through unionizing, educating the public about the origins of food, and pressuring farms and companies through boycotts, petitions, and publicity. Includes materials from UFW campaigns and boycotts that Preiss helped organize in Durham, such as Campbell's, Gallo wines, Prime mushrooms, strawberries, California grapes, and Mt. Olive pickles. Includes publications and photographs from visits from labor organizers such as Cesar Chavez and Dolores Huerta. Also present are materials from labor issues such as pesticide use, migrant education, the H-2 Workers program, child labor, slavery, and farmworker health.
RL.01047
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Joan Preiss Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Biographical and Historical Note
Joan Papert Preiss (pronounced Jo-anne Pa-pert Price) was born in New York City on January 4, 1925, and lived throughout the country before settling with her husband, Jack Preiss, in Durham in 1959. She attended an organizational meeting for a United Farm Workers support group on August 23, 1973, that resulted in the formation of the Triangle Friends of the United Farm Workers, which she chaired until her retirement in the 2000s. Preiss also joined the National Farm Worker Ministry as a board member, and was a member of the N.C. Council of Churches' Farmworker Ministry Committee. Other organizations that she and the Triangle Friends have worked with include the Student Action for Farmworkers, the Farm Labor Organizing Committee, and the Farmworkers Advocacy Network.
Abbreviations of organizations frequently found in the collection:
FAN: Farmworkers Advocacy Network
FLOC: Farm Labor Organizing Committee
FMC or FWMC: Farmworker Ministry Committee
GWFC: Grape Workers and Farmers Coalition
NAFO: National Association of Farmworker Organizations
NCCoC: North Carolina Council of Churches
NFWM: National Farm Worker Ministry
PCUN: Pineros y Campesinos Unidos del Noroeste/Northwest Treeplanters and Farmworkers United
SACSM: NC State Advisory Committee on Services to Migrants
SAF: Student Action for Farmworkers
TFUFW: Triangle Friends of United Farm Workers
UFW: United Farm Workers
Collection Overview
Materials in this collection represent both Joan Preiss's personal papers as well as organizational materials from the various groups that she worked with throughout her career. Heavily represented are the activities of the Triangle Friends of the United Farm Workers, which Preiss managed from her house in Durham, N.C. Materials from the TFUFW include meeting minutes, administrative files, publicity and flyers, newsletters, and other miscellaneous papers. Preiss's own organizational notes and agendas are heavily mixed in with official materials from the organization, reflecting the large role that she played in its activities. The majority of files center around the TFUFW's various campaigns and boycotts, which included California grapes, Gallo wine, Prime brand mushrooms, Driscoll and other brands of strawberries, Campbell's products, Red Coach lettuce, and Mt. Olive pickles. Of these, the largest amount of material appears to be from the Mt. Olive boycott, presumably because it lasted for about five years and was one of the last boycotts that Preiss participated in. Materials from these boycotts include leaflets, news clippings, flyers, posters, petitions, endorsements, and photographs of TFUFW members (including Preiss) demonstrating and distributing literature at area grocery stores, frequently wearing costumes or tiaras to draw attention. Along with protesting to the companies themselves, TFUFW frequently targeted the sellers of boycotted products, resulting in a plethora of material about various North Carolina grocery stores and supermarket chains, including Kroger, Wellspring/Whole Foods, Harris Teeter, and Food Lion. Preiss's correspondence with store owners and managers, copies of customer petitions, and information about the various chains are present in the collection. In a similar vein are the materials regarding Duke University's participation (or lack thereof) in both the Red Coach lettuce and the Mt. Olive pickle boycotts, and the Preiss's lobbying towards both students and Duke administration to stop selling and serving boycotted products.
Other labor advcocacy groups are also well-represented in the collection, and frequently the materials from different organizations are mixed together, as Preiss worked with each of them. The Farm Labor Organizing Committee was another organizer of consumer boycotts and protests, and TFUFW activities were often in support of FLOC's goals. FLOC was heavily involved in the Mt. Olive pickle boycott. Also included in the collection are administrative and organizational materials from the National Farm Worker Ministry, such as board meetings, conferences, and publications. In addition, Preiss was very involved in the Farmworker Ministry Committee, and its publications, newsletters, and meeting minutes are also present in the collection.
Aside from boycotting products, these labor groups were active in attempting to improve working conditions for farm workers, through petitions, educating the public through publications and protests, lobbying for legal protection, and marching and organizing to gain attention from the media. Farmworker issues heavily represented in the collection include the use of pesticides and its harmful effects on farm workers and consumers; the H-2A program, undocumented workers, and the abuse of immigrants on North Carolina farms; the attempts to establish a North Carolina anti-slavery law; child labor, particularly of migrant children; occupational safety and hazards in agriculture; violence towards farmworkers attempting to unionize; and obtaining fair contracts for farmworkers to prevent employer abuse. Material formats for documenting these campaigns include newspaper clippings, brochures and leaflets, copies of proposed laws, reports from farm bureaus and other government authorities, and other administrative files such as meeting minutes. Along with Preiss's local organizations, she frequently received updates on these issues from national groups like the UFW, and those newsletters and correspondence are present in the collection as well.
Along with her involvement in different local and national labor organizations, the collection also reflects Preiss's interests in the city of Durham. Although materials from her community involvement in Durham revitalization, Duke Campus Ministry, political campaigns, community health, and human rights issues are not overwhelmingly large, they are substantive enough to offer insights into her activities outside of (or in parallel to) the labor movement.
Collection Arrangement
This collection has been minimally processed; items have have only been refoldered when required for preservation or access. The materials and files were organized by Preiss in her Durham home office, and although different filing cabinet drawers have been grouped together in the finding aid, in general the collection is fairly loose in its arrangement. Loose series have been created intellectually in this finding aid to help researchers interested in only one portion of the collection. Due to the minimal processing, folders have not been united across boxes, and therefore different series are sometimes spread across several boxes. Preiss appears to have maintained name and subject files, but these folders often included a broad scope of information. Similar subjects frequently appeared in several different drawers in her filing cabinets, and organizational files appear to have been spread around the room; therefore, different chronological pieces of the same organization or subject are often present in several boxes throughout the collection.
Subject Headings
Preiss, Joan Papert; Chavez, Cesar, 1927-1993; Huerta, Dolores, 1930-; AFL-CIO; United Farm Workers; Farm Labor Organizing Committee (Ohio); North Carolina Council of Churches -- Farmworker Ministry Commission; National Farm Worker Ministry (U.S.); Labor unions -- Organizing; Boycotts -- United States; Supermarkets -- North Carolina; Pesticides -- Agriculture; Migrant agricultural laborers -- North Carolina; Spraying and dusting residues in agriculture; Child labor -- 20th century; Durham (N.C.) -- History; Videotapes; Cassette tapes; Photographs
Contents of Collection
- Subject Files A, 1980s-2006, (12 boxes)
  There are two subject file series in this collection--Subject Files A, and Subject Files B--reflecting the organization that Preiss maintained in her home office. Subject Files A appears to be better organized and the majority of materials date from the mid-1980s through 2006. Subject Files B is more loosely organized and dates largely from the 1970s-1980s. Subjects are repeated in both series and elsewhere throughout the collection.
  - About Us (TFUFW) (Box 1)
  - Accommodations/application forms (for UFW retreats and meetings) (Box 1)
  - Advertising information (Box 1)
  - Advocacy information (Box 1)
  - AFL-CIO film series, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Agriculture (Box 1)
  - Agriculture clippings (Box 1)
  - Agriculture Resource Center: PESTed News, 1992-1999 (Box 1)
  - Alambrista (film) correspondence (Box 1)
  - Luis Alvarenga (Box 1)
  - Activities reports of the UFW, 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  - Americans for Safe Food (Box 1)
  - Amnesty (Box 1)
  - APPLES program, UNC (Box 1)
  - Applicants and interviews for UFW (Box 1)
  - Artwork (Box 1)
  - Articles that are anti-Cesar Chavez/UFW (plus responses) (Box 1)
  - Articles on child labor (Box 1)
  - Articles on Cesar Chavez (Box 1)
  - Articles on Cesar Chavez's death, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Articles on farm workers elsewhere (Box 1)
  - Articles on food, food companies, and growers (Box 1)
  - Articles on farm workers in North Carolina (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Articles, general (Box 1)
  - Articles about labor issues (Box 2)
  - Balloons (used in boycotts) (Box 2)
  - Bibliographies and booklets about boycotts (Box 2)
  - Biographical information (about Preiss and other UFW officers) (Box 2)
  - Boycotts (Box 2)
    - Boycott of Ste. Michelle wines (Box 2)
    - Famous people boycott grapes (paintings) (Box 2)
    - Endorsements of UFW work and its boycotts (Box 2)
    - Boycott Project plan, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Grape boycott, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Grape boycott at Duke, 1988-1995 (Box 2)
    - Wrath of Grapes/A&P campaign (Box 2)
    - Grape boycott, Mt. Olive boycott, and Prime mushroom boycott endorsements, 1985-1999 (Box 2)
    - Pavich grapes papers, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
    - Boycott Strategy Committee meetings, 1984-1986 (Box 2)
    - Brainstorming with Matt, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Button design, Mt. Olive boycott, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Grocery stores (Box 2)
      - A&P, 1981-1988 (Box 2)
      - A&P research campaign, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Byrds and the Fresh Market, 1989 (Box 2)
      - Coop (PICF-Durham), 1986-1998 (Box 2)
      - Food Towne (pre-Food Lion) lettuce boycott, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
      - Food Lion: infant formulas and Mt. Olive boycotts, 1982-2003 (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Foster's (Box 2)
      - Food World/Harris Teeter, 1981-1998 (Box 2)
      - Harris Teeter and shopping centers, 1999-2003 (Box 2)
      - Kroger's, 1977-2003 (Box 2)
      - Weaver Street Market (Box 2)
      - Wellspring/Whole Foods (regarding grapes, worker conditions at farms), 1991-2005 (3 folders) (Box 2)
      - Winn Dixie, 1998-2004 (Box 2)
  - Cablevision, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Campus talk strategies, 1989 and undated (Box 2)
  - Canciones por la Causa-Mt. Olive pickles, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Cartoons by Preiss, 1981-1997 (Box 2)
  - Catalogues, 1995-2005 (Box 3)
  - CBS Evening News, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Cesar Chavez stamp, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Child labor, 1991-1997 (Box 3)
  - Church congregations, 1980-1995 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Methodist-UMC information (Box 3)
  - Lutherans (Box 3)
  - Church Women United, 1983-1989 (Box 3)
  - Christian disaster response, Hurricane Fran, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Duke Chronicle, other newspapers, covering protests and the UFW, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Commission on Agricultural Workers hearings, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Contracts and coverage plans, 1975-1985 (Box 3)
  - Course at UNC (HEED 232), 1987 (Box 3)
  - Creative Organizing workshop, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Cultivator, 1995-2001 (Box 3)
  - A Day Without Sunshine, 1976-1981 (Box 3)
  - DMV picket and meeting, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
    Regarding Preiss's involvement in a protest against the NC Department of Motor Vehicles discrimination against immigrants, especially Spanish-speaking populations.
  - Delegation visits to farms, 1995-1999 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 1975-1998 (6 folders) (Box 3)
  - Durham Central Labor Union, 1994-1997 (Box 3)
  - Election results, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Episcopal diocese meeting of farmworker ministries and groups, 1994 (Box 3)
  - ETG specialty advertising (Box 3)
  - Facts about farmworkers (Box 3)
  - FAN designs, Mt. Olive (Box 3)
  - Farm Bureau, 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Grape Workers and Farmers Coalition, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Chronicle article on GWFC and the grape boycott, 1994 (Box 3)
  - NC Farmworker Council, 1984-1999 (Box 4)
  - NC Farmworker Council annual reports, 1985-1989 (Box 4)
  - Farmworker festival, 1989 (Box 4)
  - NC Farmworker information: NC Council of Churches FMC, 1977-1989 (Box 4)
  - Farmworker legal services, 1977-2004 (Box 4)
  - The Fight in the Fields (biography of Cesar Chavez), 1996 (Box 4)
  - Films and film premieres, 1980-1992 (Box 4)
  - Duke Campus Ministry, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Department of Labor meetings, 1992 (Box 4)
  - FMC, 1990-2005 (12 folders) (Box 4)
    Includes expense reports, meeting minutes, and handouts/flyers/brochures.
  - FMC, 1972-1994 (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Migrant Ministry Committee meeting, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Farmworker Services Coordination Committee, 1995-1998 (Box 5)
  - Field sanitation (Box 5)
    - HR 4029, 1986 (Box 5)
    - HR 329, 1986 (Box 5)
    - HR 3295, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Copies of messages to Brooks and legislators (Box 5)
    - 1981-1988 (6 folders) (Box 5)
    - Field Sanitation Act: Illinois, 1983 (Box 5)
  - FLOC, 1988-1993 and undated (8 folders) (Box 5)
    Includes reports, resolutions, human billboarding, and press articles.
  - FLOC mailings, 1983-1986 (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Perspectives on Food and Hunger course, 1979-1999 (20 folders) (Box 6)
  - Hunger and malnutrition among farmworkers, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising, 1980s (Box 6)
  - Carmelo Fuentes lawsuit, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
  - Fund for Southern Communities, 1986-1990 (Box 6)
  - Funding for Southern Communities, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising/Resist, Inc. grants, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising/pennies, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Gift catalogue, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Grapes of Wrath, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Grassroots fund, 2002 (Box 6)
  - H-2A Program/GAO, 1997 (Box 6)
  - H-2A legislation, 1998 (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - H-2A article, Mother Jones, 2001 (Box 6)
  - H-2A fact sheets/labor information, 1989-1991 (Box 6)
  - Health information (Box 6)
  - Harvest of Shame (Box 6)
  - Heinz U.S.A., 1986 (Box 6)
  - Raymundo Hernandez's death, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Hispanic articles, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Hispanic Association, 1983 (Box 6)
  - House Course, NC Action for Farmworkers, undated (Box 6)
  - House meeting, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Housing regulations, 1977-1990 (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - House meeting, 2000 (Box 7)
  - How to Support NC Farmworkers (Box 7)
  - Dolores Huerta, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Hunger/poverty, 1980-2003 (Box 7)
  - Ideas, 1983 (Box 7)
  - H-2A information, 1989-1992 (Box 7)
  - Inglehart Designs, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Images and dialogue, 1990 (Box 7)
  - IHM retreat (Box 7)
  - Images of Labor exhibit, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Immigration (Box 7)
  - Independent Advertisements (Box 7)
  - Investigative research manuals (Box 7)
  - IRS information, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Job orders, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Labor Heritage Foundation, 1986-2002 (Box 7)
  - Arts Exchange, 2002 (Box 7)
  - La Paz mailings, 1974-1980 (Box 7)
  - Leadership program (Duke), 1987 (Box 7)
  - Leafletting celebration, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Leaflets and leafletting, 1980s (Box 7)
  - Leaflets (new) boycotts: grapes and mushrooms (Box 7)
  - Leaflets in Spanish (Box 7)
  - Legal (Box 7)
  - Legislators, 1980s-2002 (Box 7)
  - Letters to the editor/published, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - Letters to the editor, 1992-1994 (Box 7)
  - Let Us Now Praise Famous Men, Documentary Studies, Duke, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Charlotte phone trees and lists, undated (Box 7)
  - Master mailing lists, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Mailing list information, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Mailing list newsletter/media lists, 1991-1997 (Box 7)
  - Mailing lists (early), 1980s (Box 7)
  - Martyrs (Box 8)
  - Mechanization (Box 8)
  - Media information (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Media seminar, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Methodist Committee meeting, 2000 (Box 8)
  - Michigan Farm Worker Ministry, 1981-2001 (Box 8)
  - Migrant information, NC, 1978 (Box 8)
  - Migrant Health Program, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Migrant Housing bulletin, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Urbano Ramiriz Miranda, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Migrant Legal Action Program, Inc., 1980-1983 (Box 8)
  - National Farmworkers Service Center, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Migrant Clinicians Network (Box 8)
  - National Interfaith Committee for Worker Justice, Faithworks newsletter, 1997-2004 (Box 8)
  - NC Council of Churches, 1978-2003 (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - NCCoC House of Delegates, 2000 (Box 8)
  - NC DMV campaign, 1993 (Box 8)
  - NC Independent, 1994 (Box 8)
  - NC Growers Association news conference, 1999 (Box 8)
  - NCGA, 1999 (Box 8)
  - NC Occupational Safety and Health, 1990-2002 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters, 1973-2004 (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Newsletters from other cities, 1977-2004 (Box 8)
  - NFWM (Box 8)
    - NC notecards, undated (Box 8)
    - Conference call, 2002 (Box 8)
    - 2001 (Box 8)
    - Board meeting, 2004 July (Box 8)
    - 2003-2004 (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Board meeting, 2003 June (Box 8)
    - Conference call and meeting, 2001 (Box 8)
    - Board meetings, 2000-2002 (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - NFWM (Box 9)
    - Board meetings, 1999 (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Delegation report on labor camps, 1999 (Box 9)
    - Press releases, 1978-1992 (Box 9)
    - Materials, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
    - Board meeting, 1997 December (Box 9)
    - Quincy mushrooms march/rally, 1997 June (Box 9)
    - Board meeting, 1997 April (Box 9)
    - Brochure and correspondence, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Board meeting, 2003 December (Box 9)
    - Board meeting, 1996 December (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Executive director David Crumps visit, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Board meetings, 1992-1996 (5 folders) (Box 9)
    - Newsletters, 2001-2002 (Box 9)
  - Nickel/pickle campaign, Mt. Olive boycott (Box 9)
  - Nonviolence (Box 9)
  - Notes and quotes from other speakers (Box 9)
  - Notecards (Box 9)
  - Daniel Opukac (Box 9)
  - Organizing: materials and ideas, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Edward Owen, 1992-1995 (Box 9)
  - News conference, H-2A (Box 9)
  - Michael Paredes, 2000-2001 (Box 9)
  - Peregrinacion, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Pesticide board, 1994-1997 (Box 9)
  - Pictsweet (mushrooms), 2000-2001 (Box 9)
  - PCUN Oregon farmworkers, 1992-2003 (Box 9)
  - Pesticides protests (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Pesticide Advisory Commission (PAC), 1994-1997 (Box 10)
  - Pesticide conferences and meetings, 1988-1994 (Box 10)
  - Meg Phipps, Commissioner of Agriculture, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Pesticides/TFUFW (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Photographs (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Photographs of migrant housing camps (Box 10)
  - Prime mushrooms/Quincy Farms boycott, 1995-1997 (Box 10)
  - Police department information, Raleigh, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Policy Action Task Force, Farmworker Health Alliance, 1996-1998 (Box 10)
  - Purrington designs (Box 10)
  - Quincy Farms boycott, 1996-1998 (Box 10)
  - Religion (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Resources, 1980s (Box 10)
  - Retreat, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Right to Know, 1983-1985 (Box 10)
  - Know Your Rights (Box 10)
  - Robies, Ann (Box 11)
  - Sample forms used by TFUFW (Box 11)
  - Seagle, Murl, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Season of Suffering notes, 1980-1992 (Box 11)
  - Sew-In, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - Shareholder Action Info., 2004 (Box 11)
  - Simpson/Mazzoli Roybal, 1984-1988 (Box 11)
  - Slavery case, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Slavery trial information, 1993-1994 (4 folders) (Box 11)
  - TFUFW (Box 11)
    - Baldemar Valasquez visit, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Special events, 1986-1988 (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - 15th anniversary, 1988 (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Artie's visit and Episcopal Convention, 1989 January (Box 11)
    - Special events, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Earth Day, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Hamlet, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Earth Day, 1993 (Box 11)
    - Evening of fellowship in remembering Cesar Chavez, 1993 June (Box 11)
    - Earth Day, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Dolores Huerta visit, 1994 (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - 20th anniversary, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Earth Day, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Baldemar Valasquez visit, 1995 May (Box 11)
    - La Fiesta del Pueblo, 1995 September (Box 11)
    - SEAC Convention, 1995 October (Box 11)
    - NC AFL-CIO, Convention, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Potluck, 1997 (Box 11)
    - Earth Day, 1997 (Box 11)
    - Arturo Rodriguez at Duke, 1998 November (Box 11)
    - Town Hall forum, 2000 October (Box 11)
    - Special events, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Special events, 2004 (Box 11)
    - Celebration of Mt. Olive victory, 2004 November (Box 11)
    - Another South is Possible, 2005 (Box 11)
  - TFUFW (Box 12)
    - Special events, 1974-1985 (9 folders) (Box 12)
  - SAF, 2005 (Box 12)
  - Taco Bell boycott (Box 12)
  - Tour de Carolinas, 2001 (Box 12)
  - WCPE, 2001 (Box 12)
  - WUNC 91.5 FM information, 2000-2002 (Box 12)
  - Xerox, 1999 (Box 12)
- Subject Files B, 1970s-1980s, (5 boxes) (Box 12)
  Subject Files B is more loosely organized that Subject Files A and dates largely from the 1970s-1980s. Subjects are repeated in both series and elsewhere throughout the collection.
  - Accident-FLOC, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Archives of Labor and Urban affairs, 1974-1983 (Box 17)
  - Articles from The Packer (Box 17)
  - Affidavits and evidence (by Joan Papert Preiss), 1980s (Box 17)
  - Beth Belvins, 1979 (Box 17)
  - Big Star groceries, 1979-1982 (Box 17)
  - Boycott Manual, 1982 (Box 17)
  - Boycotts past, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Boycott materials (Box 17)